Chapter 7: Enterprise JavaBeans and the EJB Container Model
===========================================================
The Term Enterprise
-------------------
  The term enterprise implies that an application will be scalable, available, reliable, secure, transactional, and distributed. 

  An enterprise application requires access to a variety of infrastructure services, such as distributed  communication services, naming and directory services, transaction services, messaging services, data access and persistence services, and resourcesharing services.

JSR 220: Enterprise JavaBeans 3.0
------------------------------------
JSR 220 (EJB 3.0) focused on the following goals:
  Definition of the Java language metadata annotations, reducing the number of program classes and interfaces required and at eliminating the need for an EJB deployment descriptor.
  Where possible a “configuration by exception” approach is to be taken. Setup of many more defaults to specify common, expected behaviors and requirements on the EJB container. Encapsulation of environmental dependencies and JNDI access through the use of annotations, dependency injection mechanisms, and simple lookup mechanisms.

  Simplification of the enterprise bean types. 
  Session beans: the elimination of the requirement for component and home interfaces. The required business interface for a session bean can now be a plain old Java interface (POJI) rather than an EJBObject, EJBLocalObject, or java.rmi.Remote interface.

  Simplification of entity persistence through the Java Persistence API. Support for lightweight domain modeling, including inheritance and polymorphism.
  Elimination of all required interfaces for persistent entities (entity beans).
  Annotations and XML deployment descriptor elements for the object/relational mapping of persistent entities (entity beans).
  A query language for Java Persistence that is an extension to EJB QL, with addition of projection, explicit inner and outer join operations, bulk update and delete, subqueries, and group-by. Addition of a dynamic query capability and support for native SQL queries.
  An interceptor facility for session beans and message-driven beans.
  Reduction of the requirements for usage of checked exceptions.
  Elimination of the requirement for the implementation of callback interfaces (This reduces the number of stub methods the developer has to add ejbLoad, ejbStore, ejbPassivate, ejbActivate in a stateless session bean).

  Annotation Description
    @Entity				Specifies an entity bean component.
    @MessageDriven		Specifies a message-driven bean component.
    @Stateful			Used to annotate a class as a stateful session bean component.
    @Stateless			Used to annotate a class as a stateless session bean component.
    @EJB				Used on the client to reference the business interfaces of EJB, the home interfaces.
    @PostConstruct, @PreDestroy, @PostActivate, @PrePassivate
    					All used to annotate a life cycle event callback method.
    @Resource			Used for resource injection, examples are: int, SessionContext, DataSource,QueueConnectionFactory, Queue
    @RolesAllowed, @PermitAll, @DenyAll
    					Declare method permissions.
    @RunAs				The principal identity the enterprise bean will use when it makes calls.
    @Timeout			Specifies a time-out method on a component that uses container-managed timer services.
    @TransactionAttribute
    					Applies a transaction attribute to all methods or individual business methods on a bean.
    					Can be MANDATORY, REQUIRED, REQUIRES_NEW, SUPPORTS, NOT_SUPPORTED, NEVER.

	@TransactionManagement
						Declares whether a bean will have CMP or BMP.
	@Column				Specifies a mapped column for a persistent property or field.
	@Id					Specifies primary key for an entity.
	@JoinColumn			Specifies a mapped column for joining an entity association.
	@ManyToMany			Defines a many-valued association with many-to-many multiplicity.
	@ManyToOne			Defines a single-valued association to another entity class that has a many-to-one relationship.
	@OneToMany			Defines a many-valued association with a one-to-many relationship.
	@OneToOne			Defines a single-valued association to another entity that has a one-to-one relationship.
	@PersistenceContext	Used to inject a dependency on an EntityManager.
	@PersistenceUnit	Used to inject a dependency on an EntityManagerFactory.
	@SecondaryTable		Used to specify a secondary table, which indicates that the data for the entity class is stored across multiple tables.
	@SecondaryTables	Specifies multiple secondary tables for an entity.
	@Table				Specifies the primary table for the entity.
	@UniqueConstraint	Used to specify that a unique constraint is to be included in the generated DDL for a primary or secondary table.

CERTIFICATION OBJECTIVE 7.01 - List the Required Classes/Interfaces That Must Be Provided for an Enterprise JavaBeans Component
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Classes and Interfaces Prior to EJB 3.0
----------------------------------------
  Each EJB session and entity bean must have the following classes and interfaces:
    Home (EJBHome) interface
      The EJBHome object provides the life cycle operations (create(), remove(), find()) for an EJB. 
      The container’s deployment tools generate the class for the EJBHome object. 
      The JNDI is used by the client to locate an EJBHome object.
      The client references an EJBHome object to perform life cycle operations on an EJBObject interface.
      For entity beans, it provides finder methods to locate an existing bean instance and retrieve it from its persistent data store.

    Remote (EJBObject) interface
      The remote (EJBObject) interface provides access to the business methods within the EJB. 
      The EJBObject exposes all of the application-related interfaces, but not the interfaces that allow the EJB container to manage and control the object.
      The EJBObject wrapper allows the EJB container to intercept all operations made on the EJB. 
      Each time a client invokes a method on the EJBObject, the request goes through the EJB container before being delegated to the EJB. 
      The EJB container implements state management, transaction control, security, and persistence services transparently to both the client and the EJB.
    XML deployment descriptor
    Bean class
      For entity and session beans, the bean class extends either javax.ejb.SessionBean or javax.ejb.EntityBean
    Context objects
      For each active EJB instance, the EJB container generates an instance context object to maintain information about the management rules and the current state of the instance. 
      A session bean uses a SessionContext object, while an entity bean uses an EntityContext object. 
      Both the EJB and the EJB container use the context object to coordinate transactions, security, persistence, and other system services.

Classes and Interfaces for EJB 3.0
----------------------------------------
  All EJB 3.0 classes are Plain Old Java Objects (POJOs) and all EJB 3.0 interfaces are Plain Old Java Interfaces (POJIs). 
  Each EJB 3.0 bean has the following classes and interfaces:
    Bean class
    Business interface (can be generated by default)
    Optional XML deployment descriptor
    
CERTIFICATION OBJECTIVE 7.02 - Distinguish Between Session and Entity Beans
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Session Beans
  The tools for a container typically generate additional classes for a session bean at deployment time. 
  These tools obtain information by examining its classes and interfaces. 
  This information is utilized to generate two classes dynamically that implement the home and remote interfaces of the bean. 
  These classes enable the container to intercede in all client calls on the session bean. 
  The container generates a serializable Handle class as well, which provides a way to identify a session bean instance within a specific life cycle.
  Container provides a class that provides metadata to the client and implements the SessionContext interface. This provides access to information about the environment in which a bean is invoked.

Entity Beans
  An entity bean can be created in two ways: 
    by direct action of the client in which a create() method is called on the bean’s home interface, 
    by some other action that adds data to the database that the bean type represents. 
  An entity bean can implement either bean-managed or container-managed persistence.
  In the case of bean-managed persistence, the entity bean stores and retrieves the information through direct database calls.
  


CERTIFICATION OBJECTIVE 7.03 - Recognize Appropriate Uses for Entity, Stateful Session, and Stateless Session Beans
-----------------------------------------------------------------

CERTIFICATION OBJECTIVE 7.04
Distinguish Between Stateful and Stateless Session Beans
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Using Session Beans
  Stateful
    A stateful session bean instance typically can’t survive system failures and other destructive events. 
    While a session bean has a container-provided identity (called its handle), that identity passes when the client removes the session bean at the end of a session. If a client needs to revive a stateful session bean that has disappeared, it must provide its own means to reconstruct the bean’s state.
  
  Stateless
    Even though the client calls the create() and remove() methods of the stateless session bean, making it appear that the client is controlling the life cycle of an EJB, it is actually the EJB container that is handling the create() and remove() methods without necessarily instantiating or destroying an EJB instance.

Defining the Session Bean Class (Prior to EJB 3.0)
  public class XXXBean extends BaseClass implements SessionBean
  {
  ...
  }
Session Bean Interface (Prior to EJB 3.0)










