Chapter 9: Internationalization and Localization
=================================================

9.01 State Three Aspects of Any Application That Might Need to Be Varied or Customized in Different Deployment Locales
-------------------------------------------------------------------------


9.02 List Three Features of the Java Programming Language That Can Be Used to Create an Internationalizable/Localizable Application
-------------------------------------------------------------------------
  java.util.Locale
    In Java, a locale is identified by one, two, and occasionally three elements:
      Language 
        This is the basic identifier for a locale. Examples are en for English and es for Spanish.
      Regional 
        variation This is a country code. Examples are GB for United Kingdom, CO for Colombia, and US for United States. 
      Variant 
        It is used for creating locales with vendor- or browser-specific code. Examples are WIN for Windows, MAC for Macintosh, and POSIX for POSIX (Linux or UNIX). 
        It is also used to allow for the possibility of more than one locale per country and language combination. Most  European countries also now have the EURO variant for currency formatting.
  
  java.util.ResourceBundle
    The java.util.ResourceBundle class defines a naming convention for locales, which should be used whenever organizing resources by locale.
    When your class requires a locale-specific resource, for example a string, your class can load it from the resource bundle that matches the current user’s locale.
  
  java.text.* Package
    This package of classes provides the ability to format numbers, dates, and messages; to parse, search, and sort through strings; and to iterate over characters, words, sentences, and line breaks
  
    This package contains three main groups of classes and interfaces: iteration, formatting, and string collation.
      Annotation
      CollationKey
      Collator
      Format
  
    OutputStreamWriter
      An OutputStreamWriter is a mechanism for converting data from character streams to byte streams: Characters written to it are translated into bytes according to a specified character encoding.
  
  Internationalization with Respect to Data Handling
    The browser running in the client’s native locale encodes the form parameter data in the HTTP request so that it is in a readable format for the web application. 
    When the application receives the data, it is in Unicode format, obviating character-set issues. 
    Word breaking or parsing can be handled with the java.text.BreakIterator class
  
  java.text.MessageFormat
    MessageFormat class is good for formatting system-level messages such as error or logging strings. 
    Here is an example:
      String pattern = "Catalog number {0}, item code{1}: has been sent to order processing.";
      MessageFormat mf = new MessageFormat(pattern);
      Object[] objs =new Object[] {new Integer(123),new Integer(456)};
      StringBuffer result = new StringBuffer();
      String message = mf.format(objs,result, new FieldPosition());

  java.text.DateFormat
    JEE applications typically persist date and time values to a JDBC data store using java.sql.Date; 
    hold them in memory using java.util.Date;
    manipulate and interpret them using the java.util.Calendar class;
    parse, format, and present them using the java.text.DateFormat class.
  
  java.text.Collator
    collation is the process of ordering text using language- or scriptspecific rules, rather than using binary comparison
    For example, a component that produces ordered lists of NASDAQ stock issue entries could use Collator to place the entries in an order appropriate to the client’s locale


Using Java Internationalization APIs in JEE Applications
  Web Tier Internationalization
    HTTP requests and responses
      the default locale for any component in the web tier is not the calling client’s locale but the actual web container’s default locale.
      The first approach is to choose a single and consistent request encoding. Therefore, if all web components transmit pages using a single encoding, requests from those generated pages will remain in that encoding.
      it is also recommended that you add a servlet filter to compensate for components that do not or forget to set the chosen encoding.
      The other approaches are to store the locale and encoding either in hidden variables on HTML forms or in URL parameters, or to store this information on the server in the users’ session state.

    Design of web tier components

  Logging and Error Messages

Chapter 10: Security
============================================================
The Java security model takes into consideration the origin of the classes, and perhaps who signed them, when it permits or denies operations.

Threats to enterprise resources fall into a few general categories
  Compromise of accountability
    In legal parlance, this is known as “fraud in the impersonation” or “identity theft.” Someone is masquerading as another user.
    UserX logs on as UserY. UserX uses UserY’s identity to make system requests and is afforded all rights and permissions of UserY.
  
  Disclosure of confidential information
    Enterprise data is intentionally, negligently, or accidentally made available to parties who have no legal “right to know.”
    Patient medical record compromised; bank account number compromised.
  
  Modification of information 
    Enterprise data is intentionally, negligently, or accidentally modified.
    Corporate money account balance modified; computer virus stored on an enterprise server.
  
  Misappropriation of protected resources
    In legal parlance, this is known as “theft of service”; the perpetrator is accessing an enterprise computer system and using the system to perform, on its behalf, services that provide illegal gain or purpose.
    UserX gains access to the lottery system and causes the system to create a winning ticket for UserX.
  
  Misappropriation that compromises availability
    The service misappropriation or data modification causes an interruption of the enterprise system.
    Computer virus causes enterprise server to be unusable; a hacker causes the Amazon.com e-commerce server(s) to be unavailable.



Java also provides some packages that can facilitate the security techniques used by an enterprise:
  java.security 
    Framework of classes and interfaces for security, including access control and authentication. Also provides support for cryptographic operations, including message digest and signature generation.
  
  java.security.cert 
    Classes and interfaces for parsing and managing X.509 certificates, X.509 certificate revocation lists (CRLs), and certification paths.
  
  java.security.interfaces 
    Interfaces for RSA (Rivest, Shamir, and Adleman AsymmetricCipher algorithm) and DSA (Digital Signature Algorithm) key encryption.
  
  java.security.spec 
    Classes and interfaces for DSA, RSA, DER, and X.509 keys and parameters used in public-key cryptography.
  
  javax.crypto 
    Classes and interfaces for encrypting and decrypting data.
  
  javax.crypto.interfaces 
    Interfaces for Diffie-Hellman public/private keys.
  
  javax.crypto.spec 
    Classes and interfaces for key specifications and algorithm parameter specifications used in cryptography.
  
  javax.net.ssl 
    Classes for encrypted communication across a network using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL).
  
  javax.security.auth 
    A framework for authentication and authorization used by Java Authentication and Authorization Service (JAAS).
  
  javax.security.auth.callback 
    Classes providing low-level functionality that obtains authentication data and displays information to a user.
  
  javax.security.auth.kerberos 
    Classes that support the Kerberos network authentication protocol.
  
  javax.security.auth.login 
    Provides a plug-in framework for user authentication.
  
  javax.security.auth.spi 
    LoginModule interface for implementing plug-in user authentication modules.
  
  javax.security.auth.x500 
    Classes for representing X.500 Principal and X.500 Private Credentials. New or modified packages for Java 5 and above
  
  javax.annotation.security 
    Common security classes to support Java 5’s annotation facility.

10.01 Identify Security Restrictions Imposed on Applets Running in a Browser
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
There are two flavors of applet, signed and unsigned. 
  Unsigned applets work in a sandbox, are severely restricted, and are very safe to run. 
  A signed applet is an applet with a digital signature added that proves that it came untampered from a particular publisher.

Before the Java API performs an action that is potentially unsafe, it calls the Java Security Manager (JSM) to determine whether the action is permitted:
  Reading, writing, or deleting a file
  Opening, waiting for, or accepting a socket connection
  Modifying a thread attribute (for example, priority)
  Accessing or updating system properties

To establish the Java Security Manager within code:
  System.setSecurityManager( new SecurityManager() );
  -Djava.security.manager

The Java Security Manager checks by examining the call trace, so if an untrusted piece of code is invoked as part of a call to a secured method, it will fail because of the presence of the untrusted code. 


Here is a list of the security restrictions that Java technology environments normally impose on an unsigned applet

  Regarding to Communitation
    Can make network connections only to the host from which it was downloaded.
    Cannot issue an RMI call to a remote object running on a different server than the applet’s.
    Cannot send e-mail to a server other than the host from which it was downloaded.
    Cannot talk to a serial or parallel port.

  Regarding to code and library
    Can utilize only its own code and is not allowed to load libraries or define native methods.
    Cannot execute any native code.
    Cannot install software.
    Cannot start any program on the local host.
    Cannot use the Reflection API.

  Regarding to Runtime resource
    Cannot change thread priority.
    Cannot monitor mouse motion.
    Cannot use System.setOut() or System.setErr() methods to redirect the console.

  Regarding to storage
    Cannot programmatically read from or write to the clipboard.
    Cannot read or write local files on the host that is executing it.
    Cannot read the system properties specified in Table 10-3.
    Cannot use the Preferences API.

10.02 Identify Appropriate Locations for Implementation of Specified Security Features and Select Suitable Technologies
-----------------------------------------------------------------------

A JEE web container typically supports the following types of authentication mechanisms:
  HTTP basic
    The web server authenticates a principal using the user name and password obtained from the web client. 
    The following process shows the conversation between the client browser and the web container to help elaborate on the basic authentication mechanism.
      1. Client browser attempts to access a protected resource by sending an HTTP GET request—for example:
           GET /secure/declarative.html HTTP/1.1 
           Host: ucny.com
      2. The web container sends back a challenge to the client to authenticate. 
         The WWW-Authenticate header contains the authentication mechanism and the security realm:
           HTTP/1.1 401 Unauthorized 
           WWW-Authenticate: Basic 
           realm="weblogic"
      3. The user enters a user ID and a password, and the request is resubmitted along with the authentication mechanism, the security realm, and the credentials. 
         The credentials are formed by concatenating the user ID, a colon, and the password and then encoding this using the base-64 encoding algorithm: 
           GET /secure/declarative.html HTTP/1.1 
           Host: ucny.com 
           Authorization: Basic 
           c3lzdGVtOnBhc3N3b3Jk 
      4. The server will then attempt to authenticate the credentials within the security realm. 
         If unsuccessful, the server will prompt again for valid credentials. 
         If the credentials are valid, the identity will be checked against the authorization constraint. 
         If the identity is permitted, access to the resource is allowed; otherwise, it is denied.
    
  HTTP digest
    The web client authenticates by sending the server a message digest as part of the HTTP request. 
    This message digest is calculated by taking parts of the message along with the client’s password and passing them though a one-way hash algorithm.
    The mechanism works similarly to basic authentication, but in this case, the web container sends back some additional data with the challenge to the client to authenticate.
      HTTP/1.1 401 Unauthorized 
      WWW-Authenticate: Digest 
      realm="ucny", 
      qop="auth", 
      nonce="7fef9f6789b0526151d6efbd12196cdc",
      opaque="c8202b69f571bdf3eerft43ce6ee2466"
    nonce, or number once, which is a value that is used by the server and is valid for the current authentication sequence only.
    The browser client must then take the user name, password, realm, nonce, HTTP method, and request Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) and calculate a digest.
    The client will then resubmit the HTTP request along with a response parameter that is the calculated digest:
      GET /secure/declarative.html HTTP/1.1 
      Host: ucny.com
      Authorization: Digest 
      username="system", 
      realm="weblogic",
      qop="auth", 
      nonce="7fef9f6789b0526151d6efbd12196cdc",
      opaque="c8202b69f571bdf3eerft43ce6ee2466",
      response="5773a30ebe9e6ce90bcb5a535b4dc417"
    
  FORM based
  HTTPS mutual
    With mutual authentication, X.509 certificates are used to establish their identity on the client and on the server. 
    The transmission occurs over a secure channel (SSL) and is much more difficult for a hacker to break into.



Authentication Within the EJB Container
  EJB containers and EJB client containers support CSIv2: Common Secure Interoperability (CSI) protocol version 2 of (OMG) .
  CSIv2 is a standard wire protocol for securing calls over the Internet Inter-ORB Protocol (IIOP).
  Here is a summary of CSIv2:
    An Interoperable Object Reference (IOR) holds a component that identifies the security mechanisms supported  by the object. The IOR also includes information about the transport, client authentication, and identity and authorization tokens.
    The security mechanisms contained within the IOR are examined and the mechanism that supports the options required by the client is selected.
    The client uses CORBAs Security Attribute Service (SAS) protocol to set up a security context. This protocol defines messages contained within the service context of requests and replies. The security context established can be either stateful (used for multiple invocation) or stateless (used for a single invocation).
    CSIv2 supports Generic Security Services API (GSSAPI) initial context tokens, but to comply with conformance level 0, only the user name and password must be supported.

  When a JEE application is deployed to an application server, the deployer defines the CSIv2 security policy. This includes specifying certain security requirements, such as the following:
    Does the target require a protected transport?
    Does the target require client authentication?
    If so, what type of authentication is required?




