Chapter 8: Messaging
============================================================

8.01 Identify Scenarios That Are Appropriate to Implementation Using Messaging
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Messaging Basics
  Message-Oriented Middleware
  The advantage of message-based applications is that they are event driven. They exchange messages in a wide variety of formats and deliver messages quickly and reliably
  
  publish/subscribe (pub/sub) Message Models
    messages are published on a one or more-to-many basis, and 
  point-to-point(PTP)
    messages are sent on a one-to-one basis. 
  

8.02 List Benefits of Synchronous and Asynchronous Messaging
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
The benefits of synchronous messaging follow:
  Because both parties must be active to participate in synchronous messaging, if either party is not active, the message transaction cannot be completed.
  A message must be acknowledged before proceeding to the next message.

The benefits of asynchronous messaging are as follows:
  As the volume of traffic increases, asynchronous messaging is better able to handle the spike in demand by keeping a backlog of requests in its queue and then operating at maximum capacity over a period of time instead of needing to service the requests instantaneously.
  Asynchronous messaging is less affected by failures at the hardware, software, and network levels.
  When capacities are exceeded, information is not lost; instead, it is delayed.


8.03 Identify Scenarios That Are More Appropriate to Implementation Using Asynchronous Messaging, Rather Than Synchronous
---------------------------------------------------------------------------


8.04 Identify Scenarios That Are More Appropriate to Implementation Using Synchronous Messaging, Rather Than Asynchronous
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Java Message Service
  Following are the major advantages of using messaging for this exchange:
    Easy integration of incompatible systems
    Asynchronous communications
    One-to-many communications
    Guaranteed messaging
    Transactional messaging

  Handling Exceptions
    If a problem occurs, an application can be notified asynchronously via the ExceptionListener interface. 
    This interface identifies the JMS provider problem details to the JMS client.
    The listening object must register itself with the JMS provider

  Managing Sessions
    Transacted session 
      A related group of messages that are treated as a single work unit. 
      When a message sender uses a transacted session and calls the commit method, the messages are accepted for delivery. 
      If it calls the rollback method, the messages are destroyed.
      When a message receiver uses a transacted session and calls the commit method, the messages it consumes are acknowledged. 
      If it calls the rollback method, the messages it consumes are recovered (not acknowledged).

    Duplicate messages 
      Clients send messages knowing that JMS will deliver them only once.
      Therefore, the JMS provider must never deliver a message more than once or deliver a copy of a message that has already been acknowledged. 
      When a copy of a message is delivered, the message header contains a redelivery flag field that will be set, telling the client that this message may have been received before but that, for whatever reason, the JMS server did not receive the client’s acknowledgment of receipt. 
      The redelivery flag is set by the JMS provider application, usually as the result of a recovery operation

    Message acknowledgment 
      If a JMS session is transacted, messages are acknowledged automatically by the commit mechanism and recovered by the rollback mechanism. 
      If a session is not transacted, recovery must be handled manually, and messages are acknowledged in one of three ways:
        AUTO_ACKNOWLEDGE: 
          For each message, the session automatically acknowledges when the client returns from a call to receive a message or the MessageListener called by the session to process the message returns successfully.
        CLIENT_ACKNOWLEDGE: 
          Client acknowledges the message by calling the acknowledge method on the message. This also acknowledges all messages that were processed during the session.
        DUPS_OK_ACKNOWLEDGE: 
          Because the session lazily acknowledges the delivery of messages, duplication of messages may result if the JMS provider fails. This mode should be used only if consumers can tolerate duplicate messages. This mode reduces session overhead by minimizing the work the session does to prevent duplicate messages.


Components of a JMS Message
  Header Fields
    The JMS message header is used to identify and route messages. 
    Each of these header fields includes the appropriate get/set methods. 
    Most of the values are automatically set by the send or publish method, but the client can set some of them.
      JMSMessageID 
        Unique identifier for every message.
      JMSDeliveryMode 
        PERSISTENT 
          delivery of a message is guaranteed. It will continue to exist until all subscribers who requested it receive it. The message is delivered only once.
        NON-PERSISTENT 
          every reasonable attempt is made to deliver the message. But in the event of some kind of system failure, the message may be lost. These messages are delivered at most once.
      JMSExpiration 
        The length of time, in milliseconds, that a message will exist before it is removed.
      JMSPriority 
        Priority 0 is the lowest and 9 is the highest. Priority 4 is the default.
      JMSRedelivered 
        Notifies the client that it probably received this message at least once earlier, but for whatever reason, the client did not acknowledge its receipt. The JMS provider sets this flag, typically during a recovery operation after a failure. 

  Properties
    Properties are values that can add to the information contained in header fields.

  Body 
  Five different message body formats, or types, allow a JMS client to send and receive data in many different forms.
    ByteMessage 
      A stream of uninterpreted bytes. This type of message body should be used to match most legacy messages.
    MapMessage 
      A set of name/value pairs, similar to a HashMap. The name part is a String object and the value is a Java primitive type.
    ObjectMessage 
      A single serializable Java object or a collection of objects.
    StreamMessage 
      A stream of Java primitive values that are entered and read sequentially.
    TextMessage 
      Text formatted as a String. This form is well suited to exchanging XML data.
    
Required Components of a JMS Application
  JMS Common Interfaces		Publish-Subscribe Interfaces	Point-To-Point Interfaces
  -----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Destination				Topic							Queue
  ConnectionFactory			TopicConnectionFactory			QueueConnectionFactory
  Connection				TopicConnection					QueueConnection
  Session					TopicSession					QueueSession
  MessageProducer			TopicPublisher					QueueSender
  MessageConsumer			TopicSubscriber					QueueReceiver, QueueBrowser

Objects Used to Create and Receive Messages in a JMS Client Application
  MessageProducer
    A MessageProducer is created by a session and used to send messages to a destination.
    In the PTP model, the destination is called a queue. 
    For the pub/sub model, the destination is called a topic.
    You can also specify the default delivery mode (setDeliveryMode). 
      NON_PERSISTENT, has a lower overhead because the message is not logged, 
      PERSISTENT, which requires the message to be logged, typically to a database.
    You can also specify the priority of the message (setPriority)
    You can also specify the expiration time (setTimeToLive)
    
  MessageConsumer
    A MessageConsumer is created by a session and used to receive messages sent to the destination. 
    The messages can be received in one of two ways: 
      synchronously, where the client calls one of the receive methods (receive and receiveNoWait)
      asynchronously, where the client registers a MessageListener and then starts the consumer.
  MessageListener
    To receive and process an asynchronous message, you must do the following:
      Create an object that implements the MessageListener interface.
      Register the object with the session via the setMessageListener() method.
      Call the Start() method on the Connection object to begin receiving messages. 

  MessageSelector
    A MessageSelector is a java.lang.String object. 
    The MessageSelector examines the message header and properties fields and compares them to an expression.

How the Point-to Point Message Model Works
  1. Obtain the QueueConnectionFactory object via a JNDI lookup.
  2. Obtain a QueueConnection to the provider via the QueueConnectionFactory.(pass a user ID and password to the createQueue Connection method.)
  3. Obtain a QueueSession with the provider via the QueueConnection.
  4. Obtain the queue via a JNDI lookup
  5. Create either a QueueSender or a QueueReceiver via the QueueSession for the required queue.
  6. Send and/or receive messages.
  7. Close the QueueConnection.

How the Publish/Subscribe Message Model Works
  In the nondurable subscription model, the subscriber must be connected at the time a message is published to receive that message. If no subscribers are online, the messages will be published and destroyed soon thereafter. 
  In the durable subscription model, the messages will be received when the subscriber is reconnected to the topic. Durable subscriptions come with greater overhead because they require additional resources to persist the messages until they can be delivered to all of the known durable subscribers.

  1. Obtain the TopicConnectionFactory object via a JNDI lookup.
  2. Obtain a TopicConnection to the provider via the TopicConnectionFactory.
  3. Obtain a TopicSession with the provider via the TopicConnection.
  4. Obtain the topic via a JNDI lookup.
  5. Create either a TopicPublisher or a TopicSubscriber via the TopicSession for the required topic.
  6. Publish and/or receive messages.
  7. Close the TopicPublisher or TopicSubscriber, the session, and the connection.


Message-Driven Bean (MDB) Component
  An MDB is a message consumer, and like other JMS message consumers, it receives messages from a destination because it implements the javax.jms.MessageListener interface.
  MDBs receive JMS messages from clients in the same manner as any other JMS servicing object. 
  A client that writes to a destination has no knowledge of the fact that an MDB is acting as the message consumer
  MDBs and stateless session EJBs are similar in the sense that they do not maintain state across invocations. 
  MDBs differ from stateless session beans and entity beans in that they have no home or remote interface. Internal or external clients cannot directly access the MDBs methods.
  Clients can only indirectly interact with MDBs by sending a message to the destination.

EJB Container and Message-Driven Beans
  MDB Life cycle Management
    Since MDBs are stateless, bean instances are usually pooled by the EJB container and retrieved by the container when a message is written to the destination.
    
  Exception Handling
    MDBs may not throw application exceptions while processing messages. This means that the only exceptions  that may be thrown by a MDB are runtime exceptions
  
  Threading and Concurrency 
    An MDB instance is assumed to execute in a single thread of control.
    
  Message Acknowledgment
    The container always handles message acknowledgment for MDBs. It is prohibited for the bean to use any message acknowledgment methods—for example, acknowledge() or rollback().
  
  Security
    Because the MDB has no client, no security principal is propagated to the EJB container on receipt of a message. 
    The EJB framework provides facilities for a bean method to execute in a role specified in the deployment descriptor.

EJB 2.1 Message Driven Beans
  With the EJB 2.1 specification, MDBs are no longer restricted to simply supporting JMS messages.
  In fact, they can be defined to handle any kind of messaging system from any vendor.
  The onMessage method now receives a Record object, which also means that something other than a JMS message arriving at a destination can trigger the invocation of the method.
  For example, in order to listen to JAXM messages, the MDB must implement javax.xml.messaging.OneWayListener or javax.xml.messaging.ReqRespListener. 
  To listen to messages from the JCA Common Client Interface (CCI) connector, the MDB must implement javax .resource.cci.MessageListener



8.05 Identify Scenarios That Are Appropriate to Implementation Using Messaging, Enterprise JavaBeans Technology, or Both
---------------------------------------------------------------------------


